### DANIEL KAPPER

WEB DEVELOPER



CONTACT



danielkapper.com



dkapper01@gmail.com



@dkapper01 github.com/dkapper01



314 226-7386



1884 Columbia Rd NW #905 Washington D.C.

SKILLS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

Ruby On Rails

PostgresSQL

#### PROFFSSIONAL PROFILE

A passionate and self-motivated learner that is dedicated to continuously expanding my skill set and experience as a Web Developer. Skilled and detail oriented coder with the ability to effectively communicate ideas, problems, and solutions individually or in collaboration with a team. Strategic thinker who is dedicated to continuous learning.

### KEY PROJECTS

- Developed a complex social media application called KiwiSocial using Ruby on Rails that utilized multiple gems, including Devise and Rails Admin. Also implemented a relational database where users could follow each other
- Designed a dynamic, browser compatible dice game using HTML and CSS which integrated multiplayer functionality by manipulating the DOM with JavaScript and jQuery.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MedModo App - Co-founder

January 2017 to June 2017

- Designed a customer development program that measured how much value the app created for users.
- Acquired evidence to assist with deciding whether to pivot or proceed.
- Functioned as an enthusiastic member of the team in a fast-paced environment.
- Communicated daily updates to team members in scrum meetings.

### Winco Windows, Inc. - Manager

May 2015 to August 2017

- Managed a team of five employees responsible for meeting daily and weekly deadlines by building a solid and helpful team environment.
- Trained and evaluated employee performance.
- Maintained inventory records and placed orders for new materials.

### EDUCATION

# ${\bf Missouri\ State\ University\ -}\ {\it Computer\ Science}$

2008 - 2011

Successfully completed 90 credits, including 27 Computer Science credits. GPA 3.4. Withdrew in good standing for financial reasons.